# Anxiang (Adam) Zhang

anxiangz@andrew.cmu.edu | 412-897-2635 | | Github: adam

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

A dedicated and self-motivated student with research interest in natural language processing, knowledge mining and machine learning. I have built comprehensive knowledge of natural language processing and deep learning. I have proven abilities in problem solving and dream realizing. My dream is to automate and understand the knowledge distilling process using learning algorithm and data-driven method. Make real impact on the world!

# **EDUCATION**

# **Carnegie Mellon University - School of Computer Science**

Pittsburgh, PA

Master of Information Technology, GPA: 3.6/4

Expected 2020.12

**Relevant Coursework**: Introduction to Deep Learning(PhD Level), Introduction to Machine Learning (PhD Level), Machine Learning on Large Dataset, Introduction to Computer System, Parallel Computing Architecture, Devops, Distributed System

## Southwestern University of Finance and Economics

Chengdu, China

Bachelor of Economics & Major in Finance, minor in Computer Science; GPA: 89/100

2015.09 - 2019.07

Relevant Coursework: Data Structure, Algorithm Analysis, Operation Systems

• National Award (Top 1%) in China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling (2017);

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Programming & Software Skills: Python, Pytorch, C/C++, CUDA, OpenMPI, OpenMP, Java, Spark
- Technologies: Linux, AWS, gRPC, Docker, Devops, Vagrant, Git

## **PUBLICATIONS**

• Yu Zhao\* and Anxiang Zhang\*, "Connecting Embeddings for Knowledge Graph Entity Typing", *Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics*, 6419-6428, July 2020

# RESEARCH AND WORK EXPERIENCE

# School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Graduate Teaching Assistant for Introduction to Deep Learning (Ph.D. Level) by Bhiksha Raj

2020.06 - Present

- Preparing recitations for regularization in deep learning. Topics include Batchnorm, Dropout, initialization, L1/L2 and data augmentation.
- o Mentoring Group Projects regarding Graph Neural Network, Music Generation and Super Resolution.

## Southwestern University of Finance and Economics

Chengdu, China(Remote)

Research Assistant

2019.04 - Present

- Graph Attention Network and Keyphrase Extraction: Designing an Attention ranking algorithm to rank text
  phrases in a document. Combined Graph Attention Network and PageRank together to optimize the ranking
  performance.
- Knowledge Graph Completion: Built two distinct knowledge-driven models for entity type inference.
   Achieved SOTA performances in both Freebase and Yago KG datasets. Published Connecting Embeddings for Knowledge Graph Entity Typing as first co-author in 58-th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics(ACL).

# Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Hong Kong, China(Remote)

Research Assistant

2020.02 - 2020.05

- Designed a heuristic tree-based distributed Auto-ML training framework using Dask.distributed, a Python distributed framework.
- Implemented successive halving algorithm during hyper-parameter tuning to attain high parallelism; Results showed 5x speedup using two 4-core nodes and 94% prediction accuracy on KC1 dataset.

## **Explainable-Games**, sponsored by David Garlan

Pittsburgh

Software Engineer, Institude of Software Research, Carnegie Mellon University

2020.02 - 2020.08

- Lead the meeting and collected requirements details with clients; iterated with clients to improve usability and extensibility of the application.
- Developed a game theory web visualization application using D3.js and Python flask. It could help researchers to understand the security attacks.
- Employed gRPC, a high-performance RPC framework, to connect our application with clients' architecture visualizer; Leveraged protocol buffers to make the interface language-neutral, platform-neutral and extensible enough for connecting any third-party visualizer.

## COURSE PROJECTS

## **Speech Recognition Competition**

2020.04 - 2020.06, Pittsburgh

- Built a character-level Listen, Attend and Spell model ans used beam search to improve prediction performance.
- Implemented teacher-forcing, variational-dropout and weight tying tricks to overcome overfitting problem; ranked 14/245.

## **Neural Network Pruning Competition**

2020.04 - 2020.05, Pittsburgh

• Fine-tuned a simple 8-Layer CNN to get a 82% prediction rate after 50 epochs on CIFAR10 small dataset. Utilized individual weight pruning method to achieve 85% sparsity and 79% accuracy rate; Ranked 12/136.

# **Fraud Detection Competition**

2019.09 - 2020.01, Pittsburgh

- o Applied LightGBM with hyper-parameter searching and feature engineering techniques to predict purchase fraud.
- Ensembled LightGBM, XGboost, Catboost to increase the performance; awarded with a Top 3% silver medal among 1800 participants.

# **Dual-Track Music Generation Using LSTM**

2019.05 - 2020.01, Pittsburgh

Designed a novel (LSTM + MLP)-based dual-track architecture for generating classical piano music, which is able to model
the inter-dependency of left-hand and right-hand piano music; evaluated different models and training tricks in
Nottingham dataset.

# **Parallel Computing Projects**

2019.08 - 2020.01, Pittsburgh

- Built a renderer to draw colored circles having sequential dependency. Utilized exclusive-scan to leverage shared memory in CUDA blocks, achieving 10 times improvement compared to benchmark.
- Applied message passing model using OpenMPI, CUDA to parallelize streaming histogram-based decision tree building
  process; applied OpenMPI gather, scatter collective operation to do decentralized ring allreduce synchronization to achieve
  better bandwidth usage and load balancing.
- Bundled 4 binned features into a 4-feature tuple to leverage locality of GPU memory access;

## Stock Trend Prediction using Reddit Data

Apr. 2020 - June 2020, Pittsburgh

- Applied PCA and sentiment analysis to extract features from 1 TB Reddit comments using MapReduce. Created cluster on AWS EMR machine and used AWS S3 bucket to store the large data.
- Trained a logistic regressing to predict the stock market trend using PySpark; obtained 65% prediction accuracy.